Guida West Papers, 1946-2006
Sophia Smith Collection
wes_048: Faith Evans sides 3 &4, 18 Jan 1984
wes_049a: Jim Evans "error taped over V. Evans" B side includes end of V. Evans, 31 Jan 1984
wes_049b: Jim Evans "error taped over V. Evans" with end of V. Evans, 31 Jan 1984
wes_050: Theresa Funicello tape # 1, 29 Oct 1983
wes_051: Theresa Funicello tape # 2, Brooklyn, 29 Oct 1983
wes_052: Tom Glynn, Boston, 21 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 127]
wes_053: Ruby Grace tape # 1, Newark, 6 Dec 1983
wes_054: Ruby Grace tape #2, 6 Dec 1983
wes_055: Roberta Grant #1, Boston, 20 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 128]
wes_056a: Roberta Grant #2, 20 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 129]
wes_056b: Roberta Grant #2, also Sue B?,20 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 130]
wes_057: Mamie Hall, NYC, 15 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 131]
wes_058: Catherine Hamer tape # 1, 28 Nov 1983
wes_059: Catherine Hamer tape #2 "about ¼ of beg. is end of Catherine Hamer," 28 Nov 1983
wes_060: Marcia Henry # 1, San Francisco "one side only I think", 3 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 133]
wes_061: Kay Hurley, Boston, 21 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 135]
wes_062: Espinola Jackson, San Francisco, 14 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 136]
wes_063: Claradine James # 1, Roxbury, 20 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 137]
wes_064: Claradine James # 2, Roxbury, 20 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 138]
wes_065: Hulbert James, NYC, 29 Nov 1983
wes_066: Catherine Jermany #1, sides 1 &2, undated [see also microcassette 139]
wes_067: Catherine Jermany #2, sides 3 &4, undated [see also microcassette 140 ]
wes_068: Catherine Jermany #3, side 5, undated [see also microcassette 141]
wes_069: Frankie Jeter, WROAC, 24 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 142 or 143]
wes_070: Dee Johnson, ANC Mothers, Los Angeles, 2 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 144]
wes_071: Marian Kidd [tape #1], 10 Dec 1983
wes_072: Marion Kidd tape #2, 10 Dec 1983
wes_073: Marian Kramer (cont.), Detroit, Michigan, 16 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 146]
wes_074: Andrea Kydd, 1 Feb 1984
wes_075: Rhoda Linton, 25 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 148 or 149]
wes_076: Pauline London, Philadelphia, 24 Jul 1984 [see also microcassette 148 or 149]
wes_077: Ethel Mae Matthews, Atlanta, 11 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 151 or 152]
wes_078a: Ethel Mae Matthews tape #2 ½; (other half) Catherine Dandridge, Chicago, 12 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 153]
wes_078b: Catherine Dandridge, Chicago, 12 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 126]
wes_079: Bobbie McMahon #1, Washington DC "side B stuck, continued on side A tape #2," 30 Jan 1984
wes_080: Bobbie McMahon #2, Washington DC, 30 Jan 1984
wes_081: Shirley McNeill, Baltimore [tape #1], 6 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 126]
wes_082: Shirley McNeill tape #2, Baltimore, 6 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 155]
wes_083: Sarah McPherson, Washington DC, 27 Jan 1984
wes_084: Bill Pastereich, Hyannis, Mass., 20 Jun 1984 [see also microcassette 157]
wes_085: Elizabeth Perry, Washington DC, 27 Jan 1984
wes_086: Yvonne Perry tape # 1, 26 Jan 1984
wes_087: Yvonne Perry tape # 2, 26 Jan 1984
wes_088: Jackie Pierce, 1 Dec 1983
wes_089: Jackie Pope, New York, 20 Oct 1983
wes_090: Wade Rathke, New Orleans, 6 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 158]
wes_091: Margaret Rose, Montclair, NJ, 15 Nov 1983
wes_092: Audrey Rowe, 31 Jan 1984
wes_093: Timothy Sampson tape # 1, San Francisco, 3 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 159 and 160]
wes_094: Timothy Sampson tape #2, San Francisco [see also microcassette 159 and 160] Apr 1984
wes_095: Beulah Sanders and unknown,9 Jul 1983 [see also microcassette 161]
wes_096: Bernardine Saulsberry tape # 1, Seattle and Hal Nelson [see also microcassette 16--copy of this cassette], 9 Apr 1984
wes_097: Coretha Saxon tape # 1, N.J., 1 Dec 1983
wes_098: Coretha Saxon tape # 2, N.J., 1 Dec 1983
wes_099: Juanita Serrano, Cleveland, 13 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 164]
wes_100: Annie Smart, Baton Rouge, LA, 7 Apr 1984 [see also microcassettes 165, 166, or 167]
wes_101: Dottie Stevens # 1, Massachusetts, 21 Jun 1984
wes_102: Dottie Stevens # 2, Massachusetts, 21 Jun 1984
wes_103: Bruce Thomas #1, San Francisco, 4 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 168]
wes_104a: Bruce Thomas songs beginning 4/4 "Soon and Very Soon"; Moiece Palladino 4/5 [begins at minute 3:30], 4-5 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 156]
wes_104b: Moiece Palladino, San Francisco, 5 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 156]
wes_105: Johnnie Tillmon and Margaret Hayes in Washington DC, 17 Jun 1983
wes_106a: Johnnie Tillmon in Washington DC {German dialogue to 6.45}; Margaret Hayes, 17 Jun 1983 [see also microcassette 132]
wes_106b: Johnnie Tillmon; Margaret Hayes "see small tape on continuation of Mgt Hayes", 17 Jun 1983 [see also microcassette 132]
wes_107a: Johnnie Tillmon tape # 1 "stopped side 2 broken", 2 Apr 1984 ANC Office, Los Angeles [see also microcassette 169]
wes_107b: Johnnie Tillmon and women in ANC Office Los Angeles "Stopped # 2 See Other Tape", 2 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 170]
wes_108: Johnnie Tillmon "Side 2 over side broke", 2 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 171]
wes_109: Mel Turner, Washington DC, 30 Jan 1984
wes_110: Jeannette Washington tape # 1, NYC, 1 Jun 1984 [see also microcassettes 172-174]
wes_111: Jeannette Washington tape # 2, 1 Jun 1984 [see also microcassettes 172-174]
wes_112a: Mabel Watley, Cleveland, 13 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 175]
wes_112b: Mabel Watley (cont) and beginning of Juanita Saddler, 13 Apr 1984
wes_113: Joanne Williams, Washington DC, 1 Feb 1984
wes_114: Margaret Willis, Columbus, OH, 14 Apr 1984 [see also microcassettes 176-178]
wes_115: Nezzie Willis, Illinois [tape # 1], 19 Jan 1984
wes_116: Nezzie Willis 2nd tape, 19 Jan 1984
wes_117a: Marian Kramer "error taped over Shirley Smith Peoples and others in Columbus, a mess!", 14 Apr 1984 [see also microcassettes 145-146, 178]
wes_117b: Marian Kramer, Detroit "Start with side B", 14 Apr 1984 [see also microcassettes 145-146]
wes_118: Celebration of George Wiley, Washington, DC, 16 Jun 1983
wes_119a: Celebration of Edward Sparer, NYU Law School, Sylvia Law, Sharon Hunt Downtown Welfare Advocacy Center, Hulbert James, 29 Nov 1983
wes_119b: Celebration of Edward Sparer, NYU Law School, Hulbert James, 29 Nov 1983
wes_120: 18th Anniversary of WRO, Columbus, OH, Margaret Willis &Colleen Shillington, 30 Jun 1984
wes_121: Memorial Service for Bruce Thomas, Port Chester, NY, 15 Jul 1985
wes_122a: Side # 3 of Bernardine Saulsberry &Hal Nelson, Seattle; Side #1 of Leola Wofford, [begins at minute 22], undated, 9 Apr 1984?
wes_122b: Side #2 Leola Wofford, Mary Louise Williams, Helen Joyce Greenwood undated, 9 Apr 1984? [see also microcassettes 179-181]
wes_123: Group interview, Seattle, [tape #3] Mary Louise Williams, Helen Joyce Greenwood, Leola Wofford, 9 Apr 1984 [see also microcassettes 179-181]
wes_124: Group interview, Seattle [tape #2], Mary Louise Williams, Helen Joyce Greenwood, Leola Wofford, 9 Apr 1984 [see also microcassettes 179-181]
wes_125: Bertha Brown, Camden, NJ, 4 Jun 1984
wes_126: Catherine Dandridge, Chicago [same as 042], 12 Apr 1984?
wes_127: Tom Glynn [Boston], 21 Jun 1984?
wes_128: Roberta Grant # 1, 20 Jun 1984
wes_129: Roberta Grant # 2, 20 Jun 1984
wes_130: Roberta Grant # 3, 20 Jun 1984
wes_131: Mamie Hall "poor quality," NYC, 15 Jun 1984
wes_132: Margaret Hayes, Washington DC, 17 Jun 1983 [see also 105-106]
wes_133: Marcia Henry [# 1, San Francisco], 3 Apr 1984
wes_134: Marcia Henry [# 2, San Francisco], 3 Apr 1984
wes_135: Kay Hurley, Boston, 21 Jun 1984
wes_136: Espinola Jackson [San Francisco], 14 Jun 1984
wes_137: Claradine James # 1, Roxbury, 26 Jun 1984
wes_138: Claradine James # 2, Roxbury, 26 Jun 1984
wes_139: Catherine Jermany #1, undated
wes_140: Catherine Jermany #2, undated
wes_141: Catherine Jermany #3, undated
wes_142: Frankie Jeter # 1, undated
wes_143: Frankie Jeter # 2, undated
wes_144: Dee Johnson, Los Angeles, 2 Apr 1984
wes_145: Marian Kramer, Detroit [begins at 8:03], 16 Apr 1984
wes_146: Marian Kramer, Detroit, 16 Apr 1984
wes_147: Rosie Lee, Chicago, 12 Apr 1984
wes_148: Rhoda Linton # 1, 25 Jun 1984
wes_149: Rhoda Linton # 2, 25 Jun1984
wes_150: Pauline London, 24 Jul 1984
wes_151: Ethel Mae Matthews # 1, Atlanta, 11 Apr 1984
wes_152: Ethel Mae Matthews # 2, 11 Apr 1984
wes_153: Ethel Mae Matthews # 3, 11 Apr 1984
wes_154: Shirley McNeill [says O'Neill] #1, Baltimore, 6 Jun 1984
wes_155: Shirley McNeill #2, 6 Jun 1984
wes_156: Moiece Palladino, San Francisco, 5 Apr 1984 [see also microcassette 104]
wes_157: Bill Pastereich, 20 Jun 1984
wes_158: Wade Rathke, New Orleans, 6 Apr 1984
wes_159: Timothy Sampson [#1], San Francisco, Apr 1984
wes_160: Timothy Sampson [#2], Apr 1984
wes_161: Beulah Sanders, 9 Jul 1983
wes_162: Bernardine Saulsberry # 1, Seattle, 9 Apr 1984
wes_163: Bernardine Saulsberry # 2, 9 Apr 1984
wes_164: Juanita Serrano, Cleveland [see also cassette 099], 13 Apr [1984]
wes_165: Annie Smart [# 1], Baton Rouge, LA, 7 Apr 1984
wes_166: Annie Smart [# 2], 7 Apr 1984--[no file tape blank]
wes_167: Annie Smart [# 3], 7 Apr 1984
wes_168: Bruce Thomas, San Francisco, 4 Apr 1984 [see also 103]
wes_169: Johnnie Tillmon #1, Interview in car on way to ANC Office, Los Angeles, 2 Apr 1984
wes_170: Johnnie Tillmon #2, 2 Apr 1984
wes_171: Johnnie Tillmon #3, 2 Apr 1984
wes_172: Jeannette Washington #1, 1 Jun 1984 [see also cassettes 110-111]
wes_173: Jeannette Washington #2, 1 Jun 1984 [see also cassettes 110-111]
wes_174: Jeannette Washington #3, 1 Jun 1984 [see also cassettes 110-111]
wes_175: Mabel Watley, Cleveland, 13 Apr 1984
wes_176: Margaret Willis #1, Columbus, 14 Apr 1984 [see also cassette #114]
wes_177: Margaret Willis #2, 14 Apr 1984
wes_178: [Margaret Willis] Columbus group # 3, 14 Apr 1984
wes_179: Seattle Group Interview #1: Bernardine Saulsberry, Leola Wofford, 9 Apr 1984
wes_180: Seattle Group Interview #2, 9 Apr 1984
wes_181: Seattle Group Interview #4, 9 Apr 1984
United Church of Christ, Economic Justice for Women Who Are Poor Consultation, Washington, DC, Jan 1984
wes_182a: Coalition Building and Faith Evans workshop, 25 Jan 1984
wes_182b: Welfare Rights Caucus, 24 Jan 1984
wes_183a: Thelma Adair, President, United Church Women B/W went W/J Jackson 24 Jan 1984 [1 side] 60
wes_183b: Roxanne Jones Welfare Rights, 24 Jan 1984
wes_184a: Yvonne Delk, 24 Jan 1984
wes_184b: Adelle Blong, Inc. Maint Wkshop, 24 Jan 1984
wes_185a: Pat Schroeder a.m. panel, 25 Jan 1984
wes_185b: Lunch panel, 25 Jan 1984
wes_186a: Shirley Chisholm and Yvonne Delk, 25 Jan 1984
wes_186b: Final Day Welfare Rights Caucus Report, 26 Jan 1984
wes_187a: [unidentified meeting or conference] 8/29 session 47, 29 Aug
wes_187b: [unidentified meeting or conference] session 55, 29 Aug
wes_186b: Final Day Welfare Rights Caucus Report, 26 Jan 1984
Related materials can be found in the Sophia Smith Collection in the Papers of Frances Fox Piven and Richard Cloward, and the Records of Arise for Social Justice, Survivors, Inc., and the New Jersey Project.
Related materials in other archives include:
The Records of the National Assembly for Social Policy and Development and of the Downtown Welfare Advocacy Center in the Social Welfare History Archives at the University of Minnesota and the George Wiley Papers at the Wisconsin Historical Society.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS 1946-2006, undated, .5 linear ft.
  This series contains correspondence, curriculum vitae, memorabilia, news clippings, photographs, and other materials related to Guida West and the Pyles family.
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1954-2005, undated, .25 linear ft.
  This series consists of a small amount of personal and professional correspondence. Correspondence from family and friends in Brazil is in Portuguese and English.
- SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES 1954-2003, undated, .5 linear ft.
  This series consists of correspondence, memoranda, and notes related to Guida West's paid employment, commission, and advisory work.
  Files are arranged alphabetically by employer.
- SERIES IV. CONFERENCES AND MEETINGS 1968-2004, 1.25 linear ft.
  This series consists of correspondence, publications, proceedings, and conference packets from conferences organized by multi-organization coalitions, and by entities and organizations in which Guida West did not have an ongoing interest.
  Materials about conferences mounted by organizations in which West had an ongoing interest are filed in SERIES VI. ORGANIZATIONS. Materials related to speeches and other presentations made at conferences by Guida West are in SERIES VII. SPEECHES AND TESTIMONY.
  The files are arranged chronologically.
- SERIES V. INDIVIDUALS 1966-2001, undated, 3.5 linear ft.
  This series consists of working files on leaders in welfare rights and friends of welfare rights organizations and related social movements at the local, regional, and national level. There are also files on individuals working in government agencies (mostly in New Jersey) charged with administering welfare programs.
  Materials include correspondence; flyers; interview guides, notes, and transcripts of interviews; news clippings; notes; newsletters; and writings.
  Some of the materials were assembled and/or created by West as part of her activism in the movement, others were collected and/or created as part of her research, writing, and professional activities.
  West's 1983-84 interviews with welfare rights leaders are especially rich and detailed, providing insight into life histories, factors which lead to the narrators' activism, details about the movement, and reflections on its impact.
  Audiotapes of many of the interviews can be found in SERIES X. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS. Materials produced by related organizations can be found in SERIES VI. ORGANIZATIONS.
  The files are arranged alphabetically.
- SERIES VI. ORGANIZATION FILES 1961-2006, undated, 18 linear ft.
  This series consists of working files on local, regional, and national welfare rights and friends of welfare rights organizations, other organizations working on civil rights, issues related to poverty and for low-income people, and agencies that administer welfare programs. Materials include correspondence, minutes, news clippings, newsletters, notes, publications, and reports. Extensive field notes by West on meetings, conversations, conferences, and conventions. Materials related to the following organizations are especially rich: Montclair Welfare Rights and Friends of Welfare Rights, National Welfare Rights Organization (NWRO), New Jersey Friends of Welfare Rights, the United Church of Christ's Welfare Priority Team, the United Presbyterian Church, Synod of New Jersey, Committee on Church and Society and Commission on Religion and Race (SynCORR), the Women's Committee of One Hundred, and the Welfare Made a Difference National Campaign (WMAD).
  Additional information about many individuals involved in these organizations can be found in SERIES V. INDIVIDUALS.
  The materials are arranged alphabetically.
- SERIES VII. SPEECHES AND TESTIMONY 1965-2001, undated, 1 linear ft.
  This series consists of texts and notes related to speeches, conference papers, and testimony given to a wide variety of audiences by Guida West. Conference papers that underwent significant revisions for potential publication, but were not ultimately published are included in this series.
  Papers that were ultimately published can be found in SERIES VIII. WRITINGS
  The materials are arranged chronologically.
- SERIES VIII. WRITINGS 1971-2000, undated, 5 linear ft.
  This series consists of correspondence, drafts, notes, typescripts, and final versions of West's published and unpublished writing on welfare rights and women and social movements, 1971-1996. The earliest materials are papers written for graduate school courses.
  Materials originally generated for specific writing projects, such as interviews with welfare rights leaders, were interfiled in West's working files on individuals, organizations, and subjects that she used over the years in her writing and many different projects. These can be found in SERIES V. INDIVIDUALS, SERIES VI. ORGANIZATIONS, and SERIES VII. SUBJECTS.
  Writing projects are arranged alphabetically by title.
- SERIES IX. SUBJECT FILES 1971-2000, undated, 10 linear ft.
  This series consists of academic papers, brochures, circular letters, clippings, conference packets, fact sheets, flyers, manuals, newsletters, notes, publications, press releases, and reports. Most are related to economic justice and welfare. To reduce the bulk of the collection, only those clippings and publications that were heavily underlined and annotated were saved in their entirety. In other instances, title pages of published works readily available elsewhere were retained to give a sense of the range of sources used by West.
  The materials are filed alphabetically using West's subject headings.
- SERIES X. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS AND COMPUTER MEDIA 1971-2002, undated, 10 linear ft.
  This series consists primarily of audiotaped interviews for Guida West's thesis research (1971-74) and interviews done in 1983-84 as part of the research for her proposed book on welfare rights leaders a decade after the demise of NWRO. There are also audiotapes of some meetings, conference sessions, and radio and television programs related to the welfare rights movement and its leaders.
  During interviews, West often used two tape recorders (either two standard cassette recorders or a standard cassette recorder and a microcassette recorder), as insurance against failure of one recorder or other technical problems. While this often resulted in duplicate copies of the interview, there are also instances where West inadvertently taped over interviews or portions of interviews in one format, but not the other. As a result, researchers interested in hearing complete interviews may need to listen to both copies.
  In most cases, full transcripts of these interviews and meetings can be found in SERIES V. INDIVIDUALS or SERIES VI. ORGANIZATIONS
  In general, the sound quality of the standard audiocassettes (tapes and digital files numbered 001-124) is better than the microcassettes (tapes and digital files numbered 125-187).
  Original audiovisual materials are closed to research use. Digital copies are available for most of the audiocassettes (see Appendix). Audiotapes not reformatted consist of copyrighted materials purchased by West. Consult SSC staff for more information. Researchers interested in accessing audiovisual materials for which there is no use copy should contact the Sophia Smith Collection to discuss options.
- SERIES XI. ARTIFACTS 1968-95, undated, .5 linear ft.
  This series consists of buttons, stickers, badges, tickets, and an NWRO pendant and t-shirt.
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS 1965-2004, undated, .75 linear ft.
  Oversize materials include posters, flyers, signs, and other memorabilia from conferences and organizations, newsletters published by various organizations (including many issues of NWRO's The Welfare Fighter), and some oversize charts and flip chart notes.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
  - General, 1946-2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1978-91 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards (Box 1)
    - General, 1985-98 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Metuchen-Edison Racial Relations Council Brotherhood Award, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ohio State Consumers Education Association/Welfare Rights Organization, 1984-85, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Welfare Reform Network, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "The Bride's Notebook," 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Carlton and Pyles families, 1952-79 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Controversy re: sale of house in Metuchen to African-American family, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Education (Box 1)
    - Columbia University (Box 1)
      - General, 1954-59 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Paper, "The Negro in Brazil," Sociology 174, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Rutgers University, 1959-78 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Adlai Stevenson, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
    - Guida West and family, 1961-66 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Civil rights and welfare rights, 1969-2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - General (Box 1)
    - 1954-89 (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
    - 1990-2005, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Family (Box 2)
    - General, 1951-59 (Box 2, Folder 3-10)
    - Stevensons, 1954-61, undated (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
- SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITES
  - Blackside, Inc.: Advisor to series "America's War on Poverty," 1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Brazilian Consulate, 1954-61 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies (FPWA) (Box 2)
    - General, 1988-2003, undated (Box 2, Folder 15-17)
    - Directory of New York City Public Officials, 1997, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - Georgetown Journal of Fighting Poverty, Board of Advisors, 1992-94 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - New Jersey Rehabilitation Commission: Welfare Rehabilitation Institute, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Rutgers University (Box 3)
    - General, 1977-86 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Training Institute for Sex Desegregation, 1975-80, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Lecture notes (Box 3)
      - "First day of class," undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Film, "Killing Us Softly," and advertising images, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Film, "The Fear That Binds Us," 1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Film "Rosie the Riveter," 1987-88, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - "Lectures on Social Movements," 1985-89 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "Organizing class on gender in protest of rape of a classmate," 1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Skylight Pictures: advisor to film, "Poverty Outlaw," 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Vision Quest Film and Video Productions: participation in film, "Welfare Warriors," 1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- SERIES IV. CONFERENCES AND MEETINGS
  - [see also SERIES VI. ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 3)
  - Churchmen's Seminar on "The Public Welfare Crisis," Greater Newark Council of Churches and New Jersey Council of Churches, 24 Feb 1968 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - New Jersey Welfare Week and " Right to Live" Conference, 16-23 Nov 1969 (Box 3)
    - General, Jul-Dec 1969, undated (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
    - Notebook (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Resources (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "The Right to Live," a conference on Public Welfare, Rutgers University and Middle Atlantic District of the National Council of Jewish Women, 29 Apr 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Fall Mobilization Against Hunger" 1971 (Box 4)
    - General, 1971-72, undated (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Notebooks (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Resources (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Children's March for Survival,"25 Mar 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Interfaith Strategy Consultation on Welfare Reform," Washington Interreligious Staff Council,30-31 Jan 1973 (Box 4)
    - General (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Notebook (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Regional Meeting for the New York, Pennsylvania & Central Atlantic Conferences on Welfare,1-2 May 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - New Jersey Women's Meeting for the observance of International Women's Year, 17-19 Jun 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Welfare Reform Seminar," National Assembly of National Voluntary Health and Social Welfare Organizations, 18 Nov 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Better Jobs and Income Conference, 16-17 Feb 1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "The Displaced Homemaker: A Woman in Transition," 28 Sep 1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "Caring/Sharing Conference," New Jersey Network for Displaced Homemakers, 19 Nov 1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "A Critical Look at Welfare Reform: Strategies for Transforming the Debate," Jun 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Women for Economic Justice," Framingham 5-7 Jun 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Organizing for Welfare Rights in New York City," Office of City Council Member Ruth W. Messinger, 8 Mar and 11 Apr 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)